(銀時)あ また!?
What? Again?!
[Today's GinTama has two stories! The first story is about Sadaharu in hea...er, love.]
[The second story is about Katsura in hea...er, his delusions. "Drive With A "Might" Attitude."]
(神楽)ん 定春どうしたね
うんこｱﾙか？
What's the matter, Sadaharu? Poop?
あ おはようございますよ～｡
Good morning!
'Morning. That's a huge doggie.
(勝男)おはようさん
ﾃﾞｶいﾜﾝちゃんやな｡
["A Dog's Paws Smell Fragrant"]
He didn't finish eating again...
(神楽)ん～ また残してるｱﾙ…｡
Gin-chan, Sadaharu has no appetite these days. He might be feeling ill.
銀ちゃん
定春このごろ食欲ないね｡
具合が 悪いのかもしれないよ｡
Any dog that eats 5 bags of dog food in one sitting isn't feeling ill. He's just stupid.
ﾄﾞｯｸﾞﾌｰﾄﾞ５袋も
たいらげるﾔﾂを➡
具合が悪いとは 言わねえ｡
頭が悪いって言うんだ｡
いつもは ７袋ね！
He usually eats 7 bags.
Maybe he's exhausted from the heat? He does have fur on his face, you know.
暑さで ﾊﾞﾃてるんじゃねえの？
顔にまで 毛が生えてるからな｡
Come to think of it, he's been looking at nothing but fashion magazines lately.
(神楽)そういえば 最近 定春
ﾌｧｯｼｮﾝ誌ばっかり読んでるね｡
Maybe he's trying to change his look.
衣がえしたいのかもしれないよ｡
He does seem hot. Shall we give him a trim?
(新八)確かに 暑そうだもんね｡
思いきって➡
ｶｯﾄしちゃいましょうか？
(神楽)じゃあ 私がやるね！
Then I'll do it. Sadaharu, I'll make you into a handsome stud!
定春～
いいおとこにしてあげるからね｡
(神楽)ん～ また残してるｱﾙ｡
He didn't finish eating again.
銀ちゃん やっぱり
定春 食欲ないね｡
Gin-chan, Sadaharu still doesn't have an appetite. He must be feeling ill.
具合悪いんだよ きっと｡
It's because you gave him a ridiculous cut. He's probably depressed.
お前が とんでもねえ
ﾍｱｰｽﾀｲﾙに刈るからだろ？
落ち込んでるんじゃねえの？
(神楽)そんなことないよ！
That couldn't be. You look great, Sadaharu. A cool biz look.
かっこいいよ 定春 ｸｰﾙﾋﾞｽﾞね｡
I've never seen a dog with a cut that makes him look like a pro wrestler.
そんな ﾌﾟﾛﾚｽﾗｰみてぇな髪型した犬
見たことねえよ｡
(神楽)そういえば 最近 定春
ﾏｯﾁｮ雑誌ばっかり読んでるね｡
Come to think of it, Sadaharu's been looking at nothing but macho magazines lately.
ﾌﾟﾛﾚｽﾗｰみたいに
肉体改造したいのかもしれないよ｡
Maybe he wants to build his body into a pro wrestler's.
He already looks rebuilt. By you, the mad scientist.
もう改造されたようなもんだろ？
お前という ﾏｯﾄﾞｻｲｴﾝﾃｨｽﾄに｡
ﾌﾟﾛﾚｽﾗｰかぁ…｡
いや… やんなくていいって｡
A pro wrestler, eh...
You don't have to do it.
(新八)どうしたらいいんだろう？
どうもしなくていいって｡
How should we do it?
You don't have to anything.
(神楽)ん～ また残してるｱﾙ｡
He didn't finish again...
Gin-chan, it's no good.
銀ちゃん やっぱり ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ｡
You're the ones who're no good.
ﾀﾞﾒなのは お前らだろう？
Why's a dog wearing a dog mask?!
なんで 犬が 犬のﾏｽｸ
かぶってんだよ！
ﾁｬｰﾊﾝに ﾁｬｰﾊﾝをかけて
食べるような 暴挙だよ これは！
It's as ridiculous as eating fried rice on top of fried rice!
犬じゃないね！
ｳﾙﾌ ｻﾞ ﾏｽｸね！
It's not a dog! It's Wolf The Mask. His favorite technique is Poison Mist.
[Note: Based on Tiger Mask, a Japanese professional wrestling character used as a gimmick in manga in the 60's.]
得意技は 毒霧ね！
おいおいおいおい
毒霧出てるぞ！
Hey, hey, hey! There's the poison mist right now!
新八 ぞうきん持ってこい！
ぞうきん！
あ～ はい！
Shinpachi! Get some rags! Rags!
Yeah, okay.
Wolf The Mask, what's the matter? Cheer up...
ｳﾙﾌ ｻﾞ ﾏｽｸ どうしちゃったｱﾙか？
元気出してよ…｡
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ…
最近は 『ﾎｯﾄﾄﾞｯｸﾞﾌﾟﾚｽ』にご執心ね｡
It's no use. He's been interested in Hot Dog Press lately.
[Note: Magazine for young men. Articles include fashion and dating advice.]
決めるぜ あのｺを
おとしちゃえよ！ 特集ね｡
The issue devoted to "Do it! Get That Girl!"
おい… ｺｲﾂ ひょっとして…｡
Hey, you think...
Oh, he's grown so big since I last saw him. How old is he now?
(主婦)あら しばらく見ないうちに
また大きくなって…｡
今 何歳ですの？
(主婦)２歳よ
もう 手のかかるこで｡
Two years old. He's so high maintenance.
I heard yours won at the recent dog show.
この間 大会で優勝されたって
お聞きしましたわよ｡
ｵﾎﾎ 違うのよ｡
Oh no, that was just pure luck. Right, Betty-chan?
あれは ほんの まぐれで｡
ね ﾍﾞﾃｨちゃん｡
(２人)ﾎﾎﾎ… ん？
(主婦)ｷｬｰ！ 化けもの！
A monster!
大騒ぎになってるけど…｡
You're creating a scene.
What is this? A matchmaking party for dogs?
ようするに何 この会合
犬のねるとんﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰ？
House pets don't get many chances to meet other dogs.
家犬って 出会いの場が
あんまりないでしょ？
犬の社交会みたいなもんです｡
子犬を産ませたい人とかは➡
It's like a social event for dogs.
Owners who want puppies find partners for their precious pets here.
ここで 愛犬のﾊﾟｰﾄﾅｰを
見つけたりするんです｡
ｳﾁの発情犬に見合う相手は
いるのかね？
Think there's a partner for our dog in heat?
ﾑﾘっぽいですけど 友達くらいは
作ってあげたいですね｡
Doesn't look like it...
But I'd like him to at least make a friend...
でも 実際は ﾍﾟｯﾄそっちのけで➡
Looks like the dogs are being ignored.
There are mostly dog owners who came to socialize-bragging about their pets and such.
愛犬家が おしゃべりするだけの
場合も 多いらしいですからね｡
ﾍﾟｯﾄ自慢したり… あ なかには➡
Some people come here looking to meet the opposite sex.
男女の出会いを求めて
来る人もいるらしいですよ｡
Socialites fishing for lovers using their pets as bait, eh?
ﾍﾟｯﾄをｴｻに ﾏﾀﾞﾑが愛人漁りってか｡
どっちの見合いだか
わかりゃしねえ｡
Can't tell who's here to find a mate.
Um...Ma'am.
(長谷川)あの 奥さん｡
違うからね！
いや 別になにも…｡
It's not what you think!
We didn't...
いや 違うの
そういうんじゃなくて➡
It's not what you think! It's not that! I didn't come here with any ulterior motives!
いやらしい感じとか そういうの
全然ないからね ｵﾚは！
だから 別に 何も言ってねえよ｡
We said we never...
It's not what you think! I was just a little lonely! Seriously!
違うんだよ！ ちょっと
寂しかっただけなんだよ!!
いや ﾏｼﾞで！ ﾍﾟｯﾄ飼うのも
あれだから➡
It's not easy keeping a pet, so I bought a mechanical dog.
からくり犬 買ったら
これが 意外にかわいくてさ➡
外に自慢しに
行きたくなっちゃってさぁ！
It's so cute, I felt like taking it out with me to show it off!
本当 それだけだからね！
いや ﾏｼﾞで➡
[Note: Hasegawa is dressed as Captain Harlock/Juzo Okita from Space Battleship Yamato.]
That's really all it is! Seriously! I had absolutely no sick intentions...
いやらしいことは
一切 考えて…｡
(ﾓｰﾀ-音)
(主婦)ｷｬｰ！ 何 このｶﾞﾗｸﾀ!?
What's this piece of junk doing?!
(長谷川)こらぁ！ 間蛇男！
ﾒｯ！ お座り！
Hey! Madao! Look! Sit!
Gin-san, machines have a soul, too.
銀さん ﾒｶにも
心ってあったんですね｡
He must've caught his owner's obsession.
持ち主の執念が
乗り移ったんだろ｡
How shallow. A pet is like family. Using it to pick up women...
あさましいね…｡
家族ともいえる ﾍﾟｯﾄをさ➡
ﾅﾝﾊﾟの道具に使うとは…｡
奥さん出てってさびしいんでしょ｡
He must be lonely after his wife left him.
あら？ ちょっと あれ見て！
Oh, look there.
(主婦たち)あの人 どっかで
見たことない？
ｱﾚよ ｱﾚ…➡
Haven't I seen her somewhere before?
She's, you know, the weather lady on Wake Up TV. Announcer Ketsuno.
『お目覚めﾃﾚﾋﾞ』の
お天気おねえさん 結野ｱﾅよ｡
(主婦)あの人も
愛犬家だったのね｡
So she's a dog person, like us...
Excuse me, could you and I... I mean my dog and your dog do it?
すみません ｵﾚと 一発…｡
じゃねえや…｡
ｳﾁの犬と その犬
(結野)一発？
一発どうですか？
Do it?
あっさり ﾍﾟｯﾄを道具に使ったよ｡
He easily used his pet as a tool! And with a pick-up line a caveman would use!
しかも 原始人みたいな
ﾅﾝﾊﾟの仕方なんですけど！
あの… ﾃﾚﾋﾞ いつも拝見してます｡
ﾌｧﾝです｡
I uh...always watch you on TV. I'm a fan.
(結野)まぁ
ありがとうございます｡
Oh, thank you very much.
Gin-chan, she's fatter than she looks on TV.
(神楽)銀ちゃん！ ｺｲﾂ
ﾃﾚﾋﾞで観るより太ってるｱﾙな｡
(神楽)うっ…｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊ！ すみません｡
I'm so sorry. She's just excited. Just so hopeless...
舞い上がっちまって ｺｲﾂ！
しようがねえな ﾎﾝﾄもう！
That hurt! Gin-chan, you said so yourself---that she put on weight after her divorce!
痛いな！
銀ちゃんだって ﾃﾚﾋﾞ観て➡
離婚してから
太ったとか 言ってたくせに！
That sure is a huge dog. What's his name?
それにしても
大きな ﾜﾝちゃんですね～｡
なんて お名前なのかな？
ｳﾙﾌ ｻﾞ ﾏｽｸね！
Wolf The Mask.
まぁ りりしくて
めんどくさい名前ですね｡
Such a masculine and strange name. Can I call you Wolf-chan?
ｳﾙちゃんでいいかしら？
Last of Mohicans Living of the Dead MacGuffin...
(結野)ﾗｽﾄ ｵﾌﾞ ﾓﾋｶﾝ
ﾘﾋﾞﾝｸﾞ ｵﾌﾞ ｻﾞ ﾃﾞｯﾄﾞ ﾏｸｶﾞﾌｨﾝ｡
Say "Hi" to Wolf-chan.
あなたも ｳﾙちゃんに
あいさつなさい！
Your dog has a name that's 100-times even weirder!
ｱﾝﾀの犬のほうが
100倍めんどくさいんですけど！
They can do it once, twice, it doesn't matter. But my dog is male.
一発でも 二発でも
結構なんですけども➡
ｳﾁの犬 ｵｽなんですけど…｡
あぁ いいですよ｡
Oh, that's all right. There are all kinds of ways. You are, after all, Ketsuno...Ana.
[Note: This is a play on the fact that Ketsuno-ana can mean butthole.]
いろいろ ありますから｡
結野ｱﾅだけに…｡
うまくねえよ！
That wasn't very nice! Not only was it not nice, it was awful!
うまくねえどころか
最低だよ！ うわっ！
A Frisbee?
ﾌﾘｽﾋﾞｰ？
(ﾒﾙ)ﾜﾝﾜﾝ…｡
Oh, we see this dog a lot on our walks...
あっ このこ
散歩のとき よく会う！
(定春)ﾜﾝ ﾜﾝ ﾜﾝ！
銀ちゃん！ 定春
このこが お気に入りって…｡
Gin-chan, Sadaharu likes her...
Huh?
あ？ おいおい… こんな
胴長短足の どこがいいんだ？
Hey, hey, what's so good about a girl with such a long body and short legs...
You have eccentric taste in women.
お前 ﾏﾆｱｯｸな
女の趣味してたんだな｡
Sadaharu, were you always thinking of her on your walks?
(神楽)定春 散歩のとき
いつも このこ 気にしてたｱﾙか？
ﾒﾙちゃ～ん!!
Meru-chaaan!!
What the hell, you giant dog?!
おんどりゃあ～!! このﾃﾞｶ犬！
ｳﾁのﾒﾙちゃんに➡
What're you doing to my Meru-chan? Get away from her!
何さらすつもりじゃ～!!
離れんかぁ～い!!
ｹﾞｯ！ あの七三分けは…｡
溝鼠組の…｡
Ugh! That 70-30 part...
The Gutter Rat Gang's...
黒駒の勝男!!
Katsuo the Black Piece
What?!
(主婦)ｷｬｱ！ なに!?
(主婦)極道者よ！ ｷｬｱｰ!!
Yakuza!
うおっ おい！
定春 ちょっと待て！
Sadaharu, wait!
Stop! What're you guys doing with my Meru-chan?!
(勝男)待て～!!
おのれら ｳﾁのﾒﾙちゃんに➡
何するつもりじゃぁ～!!
Boss!
(手下)ｱﾆｷ！
ｱｲﾂら 誰や思うたら➡
I thought they looked familiar-they're those guys who live above Otose...
お登勢んとこの例の…｡
なにぃ!?
What?!
You guys don't give up, do you?! I hope you came prepared to die!
(勝男)お前ら
性懲りもなく また！
死ぬ覚悟できとるんやろな～!!
Wait, wait, wait! You've got it all wrong! That's not why we're here!
待って 待って 待って！
違うんです！
ﾎﾞｸら そういうんじゃないです！
ﾎﾞｸらの飼っている犬が➡
Seems our pet dog has feelings for your Meru-chan...
そちらさんのﾒﾙちゃんに
好意があるらしくって…！
What?! What do you mean by "has feelings for"?!
(勝男)なにぃ!? 好意って何じゃ!!
発情期なんじゃ～！
一発くらい いいだろうが！
He's in heat. One time's no problem, right?
One time, nothing! There's no way she can handle that giant dog's "one time."
(勝男)一発もｸｿも
あないなﾃﾞｶ犬の一発➡
受け止められるわけ
ないやろうが!!
Meru-chan just gave birth not too long ago. She can't have babies willy-nilly!
だいたいﾒﾙちゃんは つい この間
出産したばっかりや！
そないﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺ 子供産めるかい！
子供って どういうことじゃ！
ｺﾌﾞつきか!?
Kids?! What do you mean?! She comes with kids?!
ﾊﾞﾂｲﾁか ｺﾉﾔﾛｳ!!
Is she a divorcee?!
I can't give my Wolf The Mask to a girl with such a loose backside!
(神楽)そんな尻軽女に
ｳﾙﾌｻﾞﾏｽｸは やれん！
Come on, Wolf The Mask! We're going home!
戻ってくるｱﾙ！ ｳﾙﾌ ｻﾞ ﾏｽｸ!!
Wait! Who're you saying has a loose backside?!
(勝男)待て！ 誰が尻軽女や!?
Dachshunds have very heavy backsides-that's why their legs are so short...
ﾀﾞｯｸｽﾌﾝﾄﾞの尻は重いで！
だから あないに足が短い…｡
Boss! This is no time to be fighting!
(手下)ｱﾆｷ！ ｹﾝｶしてる場合じゃ
ありやせんぜ！
うるさい！ だいたい お前が➡
Shut up! This is your fault for throwing that Frisbee way over here.
ﾌﾘｽﾋﾞｰ あないなところに
投げるから こんなことに…！
あっ！ なに!?
ﾎﾞｰﾄに乗りよったで!!
What?! They're on a boat! That dog knows how to date! He's no ordinary dog!
あのﾜﾝ公 ﾃﾞｰﾄの基本わかっとる！
ただもんやないで～！
女は 男のｷﾞｱﾁｪﾝｼﾞをするときの
武骨な手と➡
A woman knows she's with a man when she sees his rough hand shifting the transmission,
ｵｰﾙを漕ぐときの たくましい腕に
ｵｽを感じるんや！
or his strong chest as he rows the oars!
Boss, he's not rowing!
(手下)ｱﾆｷ！ ｵｰﾙ漕いでません!!
(勝男)追え～！ 追うんじゃ!!
ﾒﾙちゃんの貞操を守るんじゃ～!!
After them! Go after them!
Protect Meru-chan's chastity!
That didn't work, Boss! Too many in the boat.
(手下)あきません ｱﾆｷ!!
定員ｵｰﾊﾞｰです！
ｷﾞｬｱｰ!! 船が沈む～！
The boat's sinking!
Sadaharu, don't jump the gun!
定春！ 早まんじゃねえ！
If you touch a yakuza's woman, you'll be in big trouble!
ﾔｸｻﾞの女に手ぇ出したら
えらい目に遭うぞ！
I was once almost sunk to the bottom of the Edo Castle moat!
ｵﾚもな 昔 江戸城の堀に➡
沈められそうに
なったことがあったような！
Meru-chan! Don't let him trick you!
(勝男)ﾒﾙちゃん！
騙されたら ｱｶﾝで！
男のﾃﾞｶさっちゅうんは
度量のﾃﾞｶさが ものをいうんじゃ！
The size of a man is measured by the size of his heart!
Back off, you two-bit thug!
引っ込め ﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗ！
(勝男)負けへんで!!
I'm not giving up! I'll show you what happens when you underestimate a yakuza!
ﾔｸｻﾞ なめとったら どないになるか
思いしらせたるわい!!
Kagura! Step on it!
神楽 とばせ！
ふんごぉ～!!
ﾌﾟﾊﾊﾊ！ ｺｲﾂの馬力に
ついてこれるか!?
You can't keep up with her power!
あぁ!?
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ 利用させてもらうで｡
I'll just use you. It's effortless and much easier this way.
漕がんでも ｽｲｽｲ進むんで
ﾗｸﾁﾝやのう｡
させるか！ ｵﾗ！ ｵﾗ！
No, you don't!
(勝男)あぁ～！
何しとるんじゃ!?
What're you doing?!
(勝男)おんどれ 公共のもん
壊してええと思っとるんか｡
Damn you! It's wrong to destroy public property! And you call yourself a samurai!
それでも 侍か！
うるせぇ！ それでもﾔｸｻﾞか ﾎﾞｹ！
Shut up! And you call yourself a yakuza? Dummy!
させへんで｡
ふんご～!!
No, you don't!
ｷﾞｬﾊﾊﾊ！ あばよ｡
See ya...
道づれじゃ！
うおぉ！ 離せ！
I'm...taking you with me!
Let go of me!
(２人)ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ…
うおぉ～！
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
(結野)それにしても
ﾒﾀﾘｯｸなﾜﾝちゃんですね｡
That's a metallic dog, isn't it? What's his name?
なんて お名前なのかな？
Uh... His name is Madao.
あの… 間陀男っていうんです｡
ﾏｲｹﾙ･ﾀﾞｸﾞﾗｽみたいな男になれ って
そういう意味を込めて｡
I wanted him to be like Michael Douglas... That's the meaning behind his name.
[Note: In Japanese, Michael Douglas is pronounced MAikeru DAguresu. Thus, MaDa + O = Madao.]
ﾊﾊ おかしいですね
笑ってくれていいんですよ｡
Funny, right? You can laugh.
No, I think it's wonderful to put meaning into your dog's name.
いえ 犬にも
ちゃんと 意味を込めて➡
名前をつけるなんて ｽﾃｷですわ｡
えっ？
What?
私なんて 何も考えないで
つけてしまったもの｡
I didn't put any thought into my dog's name.
ねぇ ﾗｽﾄ ｵﾌﾞ ﾓﾋｶﾝ
ﾘﾋﾞﾝｸﾞ ｵﾌﾞ ｻﾞ ﾃﾞｯﾄﾞ ﾏｸｶﾞﾌｨﾝ｡
Right, Last of Mohican Living of the Dead MacGuffin?
ｱﾝﾀのほうが 100倍 意味込めて
つけてそうなんですけど！
Sounds like you put 100-times more meaning into that name!
(銀時/勝男)あぁ～!!
Huh?
あれ？ おかしいな…｡
That's odd...
We fell into the pond and were drowning...
ﾜｼら 池に落ちて 溺れて
それから…｡
And then...
あ!? まさか お前が…？
Did you just...?
ﾜﾝ｡
(勝男)そら 大変やったのう
ﾃﾞｰﾄほっぽりだして➡
That was very noble...
You ditched your date and dragged us all to shore, didn't you?
全員 岸まで運んだわけや｡
ﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
(勝男)ﾔｸｻﾞもんはな
悪者いわれとるが➡
Yakuza are called bad guys, but we respect those who do the right thing.
筋通すﾔﾂには 敬意をはらうで｡
お前 気に入ったで｡
I like you.
そやな お友達から いうんなら
認めてやらんでもない｡
I'm willing to let you two start as friends.
ﾒﾙちゃんとの交際｡
どや 嬉しいか？
You can date Meru-chan. Are you happy?
ﾜﾝ！
(勝男)そうかい｡
I see. Hey, Meru-chan, are you...?!
おい ﾒﾙちゃん
お前も こっち…｡
(勝男)ﾒﾙちゃ～ん!!
Meru-chaaan!!
(桂)というわけで
最近の幕府の動向は…｡
And so, recent Bakufu activity... Recent... Bakufu...
Hey, did you see "Summer Sonata" yesterday?
(浪士)おい 見たか？
昨日の『夏のそなた』｡
[Note: Summer Sonata is a parody of "Winter Sonata" a very popular Korean drama.]
最近の…｡
(浪士)やっぱ おもしれえな｡
It was great.
I love the main character's smile.
(浪士)主役の笑顔が
すばらしいんだよ｡
(浪士)今度 貸してくれよ｡
(桂)最近… 幕府…｡
Let me borrow a copy.
Rece...
Bakuf...
That's enough!
いい加減にせんか！
ここは 天下国家を論ずる場だぞ｡
This is a forum for discussing our nation! This is not the time for gossip!
井戸端会議ではない！
(浪士)す すいません｡
We're...sorry. We were discussing the popular NHSei TV show...
[Note: NHSei is a spoof of NHK (Nippon Housou Kyoukai) a.k.a. Japan Broadcasting Corporation.]
あの… 今人気の ＮＨ星の
ﾃﾚﾋﾞﾄﾞﾗﾏで…｡
(桂)なに!?
What?!
You're captivated by stupid shows from a foreign country!
くだらん 異国のﾒﾃﾞｨｱなどに
おどらされおって！
ｷｻﾏら それでも 志士か！
And you call yourself samurai?!
もういい ｵﾚは帰る！
(浪士)えぇ!?
Enough! I'm leaving!
(浪士)待ってください 桂さん！
Please don't! Katsura-san!
(浪士)すみません 桂さん｡
(浪士たち)桂さん！
We're sorry, Katsura-san.
Katsura-san!
["Drive With A "Might" Attitude"]
(桂)すいません｡
Excuse me.
Is the videotape of "Summer Sonata" already out?
『夏のそなた』ってﾋﾞﾃﾞｵ
もう出てますか？
We don't have videotapes, but we have volumes 1 and 2 on DVD.
(店長)ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵはないけど ＤＶＤなら
最初の１～２巻出てるけど｡
[Note: Posters say: My Neighbor Pedro and Alien vs. Yakuza.]
(桂)なんでもいいんで
欲しいんですが｡
It doesn't matter which. I just want it.
(店長)ｳﾁ ﾚﾝﾀﾙｼｮｯﾌﾟだから
売ってはいないよ｡
We're a rental shop, so we don't sell them.
Rental? I don't quite understand, but help me out.
ﾚﾝﾀﾙ？ よくわからんが 頼む｡
話題に ついていけなくて
困っているのだ｡
I'm having problems because I can't keep up with the latest topics.
(店長)ｱﾝﾀ 会員？
会員じゃない 桂だ｡
Are you a member?
The name's not "a member," it's Katsura.
会員にならないと
借りられないよ ＤＶＤ｡
If you're not a member, you can't rent DVDs.
(桂)ＤＶＤじゃない 桂だ｡
The name's not "DVDs", it's Katsura.
(店長)あれだったら作るけど
身分証明になるものある？
We can make you a membership card. Do you have any ID?
学生証とか… あぁ おにいちゃん
運転免許証とか持ってないの？
A student ID, or... Do you have a driver's license?
運転免許？
A driver's license?
[Oedo Driving School]
すいません
また来ちゃいました｡
Excuse me.
I'm back again.
(教官)また来ちゃいました
じゃないでしょう｡
Don't tell me you're back again!
坂田さん ｱﾝﾀ 何度
ここへ戻ってきたら 気が済むの｡
Sakata-san, how many times will you keep coming back until you're satisfied?
なに 今度 何やったの？
What did you do this time?
I'm sorry. I uh...hit...a ninja. They revoked my license.
すいません 忍者をね
ちょいと はねちゃいまして｡
えぇ 免許 取り消しみたいな｡
なんで 車より速く走れる忍者を
はねられるの？
How'd you hit a ninja that can run faster than a car?
落ちてきた隕石に
当たるくらいの確率だよ｡
That's about as likely as getting hit by a falling meteorite.
先生の教えのたまものです｡
教えてねえよ！
It's all thanks to your teaching, instructor.
I never taught you to do that. Are you trying to make it my fault?
何 ちょっと
先生のせいにしてんの！
(教官)だから 言ったでしょ！
だろう運転は ﾀﾞﾒだって｡
I told you... Driving with a "probably" mindset doesn't work.
"It's probably okay. No one will probably jump out in front of me."
たぶん 大丈夫だろう｡
誰も 飛び出してこないだろう｡
With that frame of mind, you won't be able to deal with sudden situations.
こんな気がまえじゃ
急なとき 対応しきれないの！
I've told you that driving with the "might" attitude is the way to go.
かもしれない運転でいけって
言ったでしょ！
忍者が出てくるかもしれない｡
"A ninja might jump out in front of me. That ninja might make a right turn."
あの忍者は もしかしたら
右折してくるかもしれない｡
If you drive with that mindset, you'll be able to quickly deal with anything that happens.
そういう気がまえで運転してれば
何が起きても➡
すぐ 対応できるでしょ？ はい！
なっ？ じゃ 助手席 乗って｡
Okay, get into the passenger seat.
What you're lacking is awareness rather than driving skill,
ｷﾐに足りないのは
技術より 注意力だから➡
他の人の運転 隣で見て
注意力を養う…｡
so we'll build your awareness by letting you watch someone else drive...
Okay? Today's lesson will be with another student.
じゃあ よろしくね｡
今日は 合同教習だから｡
どうも 宇宙ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝ ｶﾂｰﾗです｡
よろしくお願い…｡
How do you do? I'm Space Captain Katsura. Pleased to meet y-
坂田さん！ かもしれない運転で
いけって言ったでしょ？
Sakata-san, didn't I tell you to drive with a "might" attitude?
もしかしたら 合同教習の相手が
宇宙ｷｬﾌﾟﾃﾝかもしれない｡
Your student partner might be a space captain.
You must put yourself in that frame of mind.
そういう気がまえで
いかないと ﾀﾞﾒ！
I'm sorry. I was a bit surprised, so I...
あっ すみません｡
ちょっと ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしちゃったんで…｡
早く ｶﾂｰﾗさん 車に乗って！
Quickly get in the car, Katsura-san. Please inspect the car before getting in.
乗車する前にちゃんと周囲確認ね｡
(桂)はい｡
Right.
There might be a ninja clinging to the bottom of the car.
もしかしたら 車の下に 忍者が
張りついてるかもしれない｡
The car might start suddenly while you're checking.
もしかしたら 確認作業中に
車が急発進するかもしれない｡
There might be a ninja hiding behind the car.
もしかしたら 車の後ろで 忍者が
かくれんぼしてるかもしれない｡
The car might suddenly back up.
もしかしたら 車が突然
ﾊﾞｯｸしてくるかもしれない｡
Cut that out, damn you! I'm honestly here to earn my driver's license!
(桂)いいかげんにしろ ｷｻﾏ！
ｵﾚは ﾏｼﾞﾒに
免許を取りにきているんだぞ!!
Katsura-san is here to get his license because he wants to become a video store member.
(教官)ｶﾂｰﾗさんはね
ﾋﾞﾃﾞｵ屋の会員になりたくて➡
免許を取りにきたんだよ｡
どこが ﾏｼﾞﾒだ！
Where's the honesty?!
I'm here to honestly re-earn my license, too!
ｵﾚだってな ﾏｼﾞﾒに
免許 取り直しにきてんだよ！
I absolutely don't want to be around you! Instructor, do something!
お前なんかに つきあうのは
絶対 ｲﾔだ！
先生 なんとかしてくれ！
There might be a chance that two people who don't get along will ride with one another.
もしかしたら
仲の悪い２人が 一緒に➡
乗車することがあるかもしれない｡
You see? It's the "might" attitude for both of you.
(教官)ねっ？
かもしれない運転だよ ２人とも｡
あらゆる状況を想定して
臨機応変に➡
Foresee all possible situations and deal with each one as they arise, in a quick and safe manner.
安全で すみやかな運転を
心がけるんだ｡
Very good, Katsura-san. You handle the steering very well for a first timer.
あぁ いいよ ｶﾂｰﾗさん！ 初めてに
しては 実にいい ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙさばきだ｡
But you're going a little too fast. Slow down before a turn!
(教官)でも ちょっと
ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞ 出しすぎだね！
ｶｰﾌﾞ前では 減速して！
You're too tense.
お前 力 入りすぎなんだよ｡
ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙに寄りすぎ！
Too close to the steering wheel. That decreases your field of view. Move your body back.
かえって 視界 悪くなるぞ｡
体を離せ！
もしかして… ｵﾚは
緊張しているのかもしれない｡
Perhaps...
I might be nervous...
どんな かもしれない運転!?
つうか かもしれなくねえんだよ!!
What kind of "might" driving is that?! It's not "might"! You're totally tense!
完全に緊張してんだろうが！
おい!!
Hey!
危ねえ！ ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞ 落とせ!!
Look out!
Slow down!
Sakata-san, the brake! There's a passenger-side brake in these student cars!
坂田さん ﾌﾞﾚｰｷを！ 教習車には
助手席にも ﾌﾞﾚｰｷあるから!!
もしかしたら ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞを 50ｷﾛ以下に
落とすと 爆発する爆弾を➡
Perhaps...
An Anti-Foreigner Faction ronin might have rigged a bomb to explode if the speed drops below 50 kph!
[Note: Spoof of the movie "Speed."]
どこかの攘夷浪士が
しかけているかもしれない!!
How complicated a "might" driving scenario is that?!
どんだけ 手のこんだ
かもしれない運転!?
You're the Anti-Foreigner Faction ronin!
つうか 攘夷浪士 お前！
C'mon, instructor! What're you going to do about this?
おい 先生!! どうすんだ!? だから
ｵﾚ ｲﾔだって言ったんだよ！
This is why I was against this!
These things happen because this guy is serious to a fault!
ｺｲﾂ ｸｿﾏｼﾞﾒだから
こういうことになんの！ あっ!!
Ack...
おい 次！
(教官)Ｓ字！ おかまいなしか!!
Next is...an S-curve! He doesn't even give a damn!
もしかして Ｓ字の …の部分に…｡
Perhaps...along the S-curve...
(松子)すっかり 寂しい食卓に
なってしまいましたね｡
Our meals have become so lonely...
I wish we could've let Mother see Natsuko-san in her wedding dress.
夏子さんの花嫁姿 お母様にも
見せてさしあげたかった｡
She was so beautiful.
とっても きれいだったわ｡
(父)ﾌﾟﾊｰｯ！ てやんでぇ ﾊﾞｰﾛｰ！
ｵﾒｴ 娘なんてろくなもんじゃねえ｡
What're you talking about, silly?
Daughters aren't good for anything.
No matter how lovingly you raise them, they all go to another family in the end.
どんなに かわいがって育てても
結局➡
みんな よそに いっちまいやがる｡
薄情なもんでぃ｡
How heartless they are.
Oh? You still have a daughter right here, Father.
(松子)あら… 娘なら まだ ここに
いるじゃないですか お父様｡
(父)松子さんよ…
ｱﾝﾀ 今からでもいい｡
Matsuko-san...
It's not too late.
Why don't you find a nice man?
誰か いい人 探したら どうでぃ？
You are my son's wife, but that son is dead.
息子の嫁とはいえ 今や
その息子も死んじまって いねえ｡
You have no blood ties to me,
血のつながりのねえ ｱﾝﾀが➡
こんな老いぼれの
世話する義理もねえだろ｡
so you have no obligation to keep looking after this old fool.
You're good-natured and good-looking.
(父)ｱﾝﾀは気立ても器量もいいから
いくらでも 相手がいるよ｡
You should be able to find any number of men.
You don't have to be concerned about me. I can manage by myself.
ｵﾚに 気 遣うこたぁねえ｡
１人でも やっていけらぁ｡
No one would marry an old woman like me.
こんなおばさん もう
もらい手なんて いませんよ｡
Father, are you that intent on chasing me out?
お父様 そんなに 私を
追い出したいんですか？
No...that isn't why I...
いや そうじゃなくて…｡
ﾌﾌｯ… よい縁談があれば こんな家
すぐに出ていってやるわ｡
If there's a good offer, I'll leave this house in no time.
《父:そんな憎まれ口を
叩くくせに➡
Despite saying such a wry comment, the woman never tried to leave.
女は いつになっても
出て行こうとはしなかった｡
いつも口うるさく
ｵﾚの世話を焼いた…》
She looked after me, always nagging.
(男)もう いいだろう！
ん…？
Haven't you done enough?
(男)まだ 死んだ旦那に
未練があるというのか？
Do you still have lingering feelings for your late husband?
もう７年だぞ！ ｷﾐはｷﾐで 自分の
人生を歩むべきじゃないのか!?
It's been seven years. You should live your own life!
もう いいかげん ﾎﾞｸと一緒に➡
Isn't it about time you took a step towards starting a new life with me?!
新しい一歩を踏み出しても
いいんじゃないのか!?
(松子)私は いつだって
自分の人生を歩んでいます｡
I'm always walking the path of my own life.
未練とか そんなくだらない理由で
この家にいるんじゃありません｡
I'm not staying at this house because of lingering feelings or anything silly like that.
(男)じゃあ なぜだ!?
他に男でもいるというのか!?
Then why? Is there another man?
私には…➡
It's because...
お父さんがいますから｡
I have Father.
(松子)血はつながってないけど
お父さんなんです 私の…｡
We may not be related by blood, but he is my Father...
(桂)…という ﾓｸﾞﾗたちが➡
...There might be moles like that under the road...
あのＳ字の土の下に
いるかもしれない…｡
along the S-curve...
いるかぁ…！
しかも ﾑﾀﾞになげえんだよ！
No way! And that was just too long a reason!
That's wasn't "might" driving or anything! It was just your delusion!
もう かもしれない運転でも
何でもねえよ！
ただの妄想じゃねえか！
Sakata-san, thank you for stopping the car.
坂田さん よく止めたね…
踏み切り前は一時停止… ううっ｡
We must stop before a rail crossing...
なんで泣いてんの？
はい 窓をあけて｡
Why're you crying
Please open the window...
いや もう窓ないんですけど…｡
There isn't one anymore.
(教官)ここでも
かもしれない運転だよ｡
You have to "might" drive here, as well. A train might come.
電車がくるかもしれない｡
遮断機が下りてくるかもしれない｡
The crossing bar might come down. Listen to make sure.
耳で音を直接 確かめてください｡
まぁ 教習所ですから
線路はないし➡
Of course, this is a driving school, so there are no tracks,
電車は通りませんけど
一応 形式としてやってください｡
and no train will pass, but please do it as a formality.
はい… いや ちょっと待て！
Yes.
No, wait!
(踏み切りの音)
聞こえる…｡
I hear it... I can hear the sound of a train coming!
聞こえるぞ！ 電車のくる音が！
聞こえねえよ！
(桂)いいや 聞こえる！
I don't hear it.
No, I can hear it! And the sound of the crossing bar coming down!
(桂)遮断機の下りる音も
はっきりと聞こえるぞ！
I can hear it clearly!
おい！ やべえよ ｺｲﾂ！
誰か医者 呼んでくれ！
Hey, he's really lost it. Somebody call a doctor.
(桂)あ… あれは… お父様！
Ack! That's!
Father!
ｵﾚさえいなけりゃ
松子は幸せに…｡
If I disappear... Matsuko can be happy...
(警笛)
If I move now,
今なら まだ…
間に合うかもしれない！
I might get there in time!
ふぉぉぉぉっ！
(警笛)
You fool! What'd you do that for?! You were almost killed!
ﾊﾞｶ野郎～！
なんて真似してんだ!?
死ぬところだったぞ！
What good would your death do?!
ｱﾝﾀが死んでどうなる？
それを 松子殿が望むと!?
Did you think that was what Matsuko would want?!
(桂)ｵﾚといても
松子は幸せになれねえ…｡
Matsuko would never be happy if she stayed with me.
松子より 確実に早く ｵﾚは死ぬ｡
…そのとき 一人➡
I will certainly die before she does.
When that happens, what will old, alone and left behind Matsuko do?
年老いて 残された松子は
どうすりゃいい…？
ｵﾚは… いねえほうがいいのさ…｡
I...I would be better off gone...
ｵﾚがいなければ 松子は➡
If I'm gone, Matsuko would be released from the shackles I have placed on her and be free.
ｵﾚという呪縛から解き放たれ
自由になれる…｡
それは違うわ！ お父様！
That's where you're wrong, Father!
You're...Matsuko!
お前…
ま… 松子!?
私はただ お父様と…
お父さ…｡
All I want is to be with you... Father...
Father...
Matsuko...
松子…｡
お父様…｡
Father...
Father!
(桂)お父様っ！
(ﾌﾞﾚｰｷの音)
(教官)…坂田さん？
はい…｡
Sakata-san...
Yes?
(教官)かもしれない運転は
もう しないほうが➡
Maybe we shouldn't be "might" driving anymore.
いいかもしれない…｡
そうかもしれない…｡
You might be right.
(桂)ま… 松子…｡
お… お父… 様…｡
Ma...Matsuko...
Fath...er...
というわけで…➡
And so, recent Bakufu activity...
最近の
幕府の動向… は 置いといて｡
Let's leave that for now.
先日 偶然…
『夏のそなた』というﾃﾚﾋﾞﾄﾞﾗﾏを➡
I happened to have watched "Summer Sonata" the other day, and...
観る機会があったのだが…｡
(浪士)おい 観たか？
Hey, did you watch yesterday's "Changam's Humiliation"?
[Note: Spoof of Dae Jang Geum: Jewel in the Palace, a Korean TV drama series.]
昨日の 『ﾁｬﾝｶﾞﾑの恥態』！
(桂)夏の…｡
Summer...
It was great.
やっぱ おもしれぇな！
主役の子が 健気で泣けるんだよ！
The main character's so brave, I cried.
TV...
(桂)ﾃﾚﾋﾞ…｡
(浪士)今度 貸してくれよ！
Let me borrow a copy.
(桂)夏… ﾃ…｡
(騒ぎ声)
Summ...
T...
いい加減にせんかぁっ！
話を聞け！
Cut it out! Listen to what I have to say!
Don't do that to me when I made the effort to watch the show!
人がせっかく やっとの思いで
観てきたというのに➡
そりゃ ないんじゃないのっ!?
桂さん！
Katsura-san, "Summer Sonata" is old now. "Changam's Humiliation" is popular now.
｢夏その｣は もう 古いんです！
今は 『ﾁｬﾝｶﾞﾑの恥態』が➡
流行ってるんですよ！
(桂)なにぃ!?
What?!
なんでも かんでも
新しいものに 飛びつきおって！
You jump from one new thing to the next.
もういい！
ﾃﾚﾋﾞﾄﾞﾗﾏなど 二度と観るかっ!!
I've had enough! I'm never watching another TV drama!
ｵﾚは帰る！
(浪士たち)桂さん！
I'm leaving!
Katsura-san!
(浪士たち)
待ってください 桂さ～ん！
Please wait, Katsura-san!
すみません｡ ｢ﾁｬﾝｶﾞﾑの裸体｣って
おいてありますか？
Excuse me, do you have "Changam's Naked Body"?
It's "humiliation." Yes, we do. Your membership card, please.
(店員)｢恥態｣です！
…ありますよ！
えっと 会員証を お願いします｡
ありません｡
I don't have one.
じゃあ お作りしますので
身分証明になるものは 何か…？
Then I'll create one. May I see some ID?
じゃっ…
これで頼むっ!!
[Wanted: Anti-Foreigner Faction Ronin, Kotaro Katsura. Call 110.]
Use this.
[Preview]
We headed into the mountains in autumn hoping to make some money from matsutake mushrooms.
While we were there, we came across a giant bear known as
the "master of the mountain" and the hunter who pursues him.
The next episode...
"Think for a Minute Now, Do Matsutake Mushrooms Really Taste All That Good?"
[Marinosuke, a lonely hunter, pursues his rival, Masamune, the giant bear.]
[This week's stories were a bit you-know-what. But next week's story will touch your heart.]